-迪蘭 -鄧菲先生
- Dylan? - Oh, Mr. D.
你也在這慢跑啊
You jog here, too?
這離我們家就半個街區
I'm a half a block from my house.
你穿靴子跑步嗎
Are you wearing boots?
好吧 其實這并不是那么巧合啦
Okay, this is less of a coincidence than it seems.
我跟了你好幾天了
I've been following you around for a few days.
是關于海莉的事
It's about Haley.
我知道她現在正在戀愛中
I know she's in a relationship,
但是我愛她 我覺得她也愛我
but I love her, and I think she loves me.
迪蘭 我聽說了發生的事
Dylan, I heard about what happened.
要我就不會想太多
I wouldn't read too much into it.
畢竟只是一個吻而已
It was only one kiss.
不是吧
Oh, no.
兩個吻嗎
Two kisses?
你愿意這么想也行
Okay.
我去了迪蘭家跟他說
I went to Dylan's house to tell him it wasn't okay
我們不應該接吻 結果我和他睡了
that we kissed, and I ended up sleeping with him.
我想回去告訴他我們不應該上床
I would go back to his house to tell him it wasn't okay
但是誰知道那又會發生什么
we slept together, but where does that go?
反正我就是想和她談一談
Anyway, I just want to talk to her,
可是她不接我的電話
and she won't return my calls.
她在跟你玩人間蒸發嗎
She's ghosting you?
作為一個長輩 你總是這么跟得上流行
For an older dude, you always kept up with the lingo.
是滴
Word.
真為你難過 小伙子
Aw, I'm sorry, man.
你是個好人 不應該被人間蒸發對待
You're a good guy. You deserve better than being ghosted.
-我會跟她說一說的 -你愿意為我這樣做
- I'll talk to her. - You'd do that for me?
對 我會跟她好好嘮嘮 頂我不
Yeah, I'll throw her a gab. You stab me?
靠 盧克是不是亂教來整我了
Darn it. I think Luke's messing with me.
媽媽咪呀
Mama mia!
我的兒胳膊兒怎么兒了
What is-a wrong-a with-a my arm-a?
別擔心
Fuggedaboutit!
你滴胳膊好好的
Youse arm's fine!
那你為啥兒不來咬一大兒口這多汁的美味
Ah, then why-a won't you take a big-a, juicy bite out of it?
路易吉 我覺得我們
Yo, Luigi, I think what we got here
交流有問題
is a communication problem.
我說我想吃意式時 是指...
See, when I said I wanted to eat Italian...
-落幕 -落幕
- And scene. - And scene.
太好啦
Bravo!
他們剛才是即興排出的戲
They just made that scene up as they were going,
而且最后還有一個有趣的轉折
and then at the end, there was a funny twist.
下一幕
Okay, for this next scene,
雪莉會扮演一個名人
Sherry will play a famous person.
演員盧·戴蒙德·菲利普斯
Lou Diamond Phillips!
棒 杰 幫我想個職業[我需要找正職]
Excellent. And, Jay, I need an occupation.
我同意
I agree.
曼尼的虛幻加拿大女朋友竟然是真的
So, it turns out Manny's fake Canadian girlfriend is real
還很煩人
and annoying.
他回學校之前 她會一直住在這
Until he goes back to school, she's staying here
一直試鏡 準備當個即興表演明星
and auditioning to be an improv star,
就像那個誰 你知道的 沒誰
just like, you know, no one ever.
天啊 夏天這么快就過去了
Boy, oh, boy, did that summer fly by or what?
-不說了 你走吧 -拜 杰
- Anyway, off you go. - Bye, Jay.
我已經開始想你了 寶貝
I miss already you, papi.
他過三天就要回來洗臟衣服了
He'll be back in three days to do his laundry.
我也會想你的
I'll miss you, too.
過來 小泰迪熊
Come here, Teddy Bear.
-周六見 -我等不及了
- See you Saturday. - I can't wait.
好 我去樓上練習即興劇啦
Okay, I'll be upstairs, doing space work.
歌洛莉亞 一個問題
Gloria, quick question --
那個人怎么還在這
why is that person still here?
我沒告訴你嗎
Ay! I didn't tell you?
-你少來 -學校不讓雪莉
- Don't even. - The college won't let Sherry
和曼尼一起住宿舍
live in the dorm with Manny,
所以她要住在這里
so she's gonna stay here.
我要做個美味的三明治啦 你來一個嗎
I am going to make a delicious sandwich. You want one?
我不要什么三明治 我想讓她離開我們家
I don't want a sandwich. I want her out of my house.
而且被你說得有點想吃三明治了
And I kind of want a sandwich.
這是曼尼第一段正經感情
This is Manny's first serious relationship.
我以前常常跟他說
I used to tell him,
"我知道有一天你一定會找到這樣一個女人
"I know that one day you're gonna find a woman
她會欣賞你的各種優點"
that will appreciate all your gifts."
其實我也不知道
But I didn't know.
你意思是你覺得她不煩人嗎
You're saying you don't find her annoying?
不啊 我覺得她很搞笑 別擔心
No. I think she's funny. And don't worry.
她就在這住到
She's only gonna stay here
她可以靠即興表演養活自己的時候
until she can support herself doing improv.
那把她的名字也加入我們家電話答錄機吧
Well, put her name on the answering machine,
她這輩子估計都得住在這了
'cause she's not going anywhere.
韋恩·布雷迪這樣的人一生頂多碰到一個
We're only lucky enough to get one Wayne Brady in a lifetime.
我剛剛遇到迪蘭了
Hey. I just ran into Dylan.
他告訴我你們之間怎么回事了
He told me what happened between you two.
-聽著 不管他說了什么 -別緊張
- Look, whatever he said -- - Relax.
我知道你又親了他
I know you kissed him again.
可以這么說
Okay.
你顯然繼承了
You clearly inherited
我們鄧菲之吻的力量
the power of the Dunphy kiss.
相信我 那真的能讓男人意亂情迷
Take it from me. That can really mess with a man.
你不能再對他玩人間蒸發了
You need to stop ghosting him.
我知道 可是這太難了
I know. It's just so hard.
我是說 我現在和阿爾文在一起
I mean, I'm with Arvin,
我告訴他我吻了迪蘭后他就沒理過我
who hasn't talked to me since I told him I kissed Dylan,
而每次我跟迪蘭談話 最后都... 吻了他
and every time I talk to Dylan, I end up...kissing him.
反正就是很混亂啦
It's very confusing.
迪蘭是個內心敏感的人
Well, Dylan's a sensitive guy.
你們一起經歷了那么多
After all your history together,
他理應知道自己是什么身份
he deserves to know where he stands.
你應該和他談談
You should talk to him.
好吧 我讓他過來
Fine. I'll tell him to come over.
用河豚表情
Use the blowfish emoji.
意思是"準備迎接壞消息吧"
It means, "Brace yourself for some bad news."
-不 不是那個意思 -盧克
- No, it doesn't. - Luke.
不行 不行
Hey, hey, no, no.
我說過今天不許再看視頻了 好嗎
I said no more screen time today, okay?
再說了卡車視頻能有什么吸引人的
What's so fascinating about truck videos, anyway?
惹火消防員呢
Ooh, firemen.
好了 莉莉 我們走吧
All right, Lily, let's go.
我們有多晚
Okay, how late are we --
"屋內丟羊"那種晚
"Goat loose in the house" Late
還是"路中蠻牛"那種晚
or "Stubborn cow in the road" Late?
你都在這住了二十年了 說人話行嗎
You've lived here 20 years. Please use city time.
卡爾 卡爾 卡爾 卡爾
Oh, Cal, Cal, Cal, Cal!
不要啊 你灑了一地
No, you're spilling all over the floor!
莉莉 你走路能看看路嗎
Hey, Lily, can you watch where you're going?
行 麻煩都賴我行了吧
Yeah, I'm the problem.
現在我們得給他換鞋了
Now we're gonna have to change his shoes.
不對 他不能穿其他鞋
No, he can't wear his other shoes
因為他拿蠟筆在上面亂寫亂畫
because he scribbled on those in crayon
看上去像納粹十字符一樣 在今天這個時代
and it looks like a swastika, and in this day and age...
不僅僅是當今時代
Not just this day and age.
行了 他的鞋沒事 他們也有孩子
Okay. His shoes are fine. They have kids.
他們知道孩子會毀了一切
They know they ruin everything.
-除了你的生活 -對
- Except your life. - Yeah.
圓得不錯
Nice save.
我們辦公室的另一個助理地檢 特倫特
Another Assistant District Attorney in my office, Trent,
邀請我們共進午餐 這簡直太好了
invited us over for lunch, which is great
因為他在找一個次席律師
because he is looking for a second chair
一起處理一個受人矚目的案子 我想加入
on a very high-profile case, and I want in.
知道嗎 我以前是蚱蜢高中
You know, I was second-chair washboard
交響樂團的搓衣板次席
in the Grasshopper High School orchestra.
你繼續
Go on.
是這樣的 特蘭特和我有好多共同點
So, Trent and I have so much in common.
他的丈夫也在學校工作 就像小卡一樣
His husband works in a school, just like Cam,
他們也有兩個小孩
and they have two young kids.
我的意思是 要是有個同志律師交友網
I mean, if there was a gay lawyer dating site,
我們絕對能完美配對
we'd be a perfect match.
那可以叫懸案[巨根]陪審團網
It could be called HungJuries.Com.
行吧 走之前把這些爛哏都先說完
Good. So, get all that out before we go.
歡迎 請進 你一定就是小卡了
Welcome. Come in. You must be Cam.
-你好 -你好 我是特蘭特
- Hi. - Hi. I'm Trent.
這是我的丈夫 基蘭
This is my husband -- Kieran.
你好 很高興見到你們 這是莉莉和卡爾
Hi. Nice to meet you. This is Lily and Cal.
不好意思我們遲到了
Sorry we're late.
這倆個家伙在車上小吵小鬧了一陣兒
These two got into a little spat in the car,
我們不得不靠邊停下車 所以
and we had to pull over, so...
他朝我臉上打嗝
He burped in my face.
誰讓你當時正看著我
You were looking at me.
好了 好了 第二輪又來了
Great, great. Round 2.
我相信你們懂的
I'm sure you guys get it.
當然 我們的小家伙在車里更鬧騰
Oh, totally. Our little ones are even worse in the car.
我去把他們帶過來讓孩子們一起玩
Oh, I'll go get them so the kids can play.
你們的房子 可真是 真是 真漂亮
Wow. Your house, it's -- it's -- it's beautiful.
而且 天啊 這個盤子太美了
And -- Oh, my God, this plate is gorgeous.
謝謝夸獎 我們在尼泊爾
Oh, thank you. Yeah, we got that in Nepal
一個童女神慶典節日上買的
at a festival celebrating the child goddess Kumari.
我和童[童年]女神最近的一次接觸
Oh, well, the closest I've been to a child goddess
就是我的女星茱兒·芭莉摩午餐盒
was my Drew Barrymore lunch box.
老天 你們的房子好干凈
God, your house is so clean!
你們有孩子是怎么讓它保持這么干凈的
How do you keep it so clean with kids?
它們來啦
Here they are.
這是德文和丹妮詩
This is Devon and Denise.
這 這是你的 這就是你的孩子
Th-Those are your -- Those are your kids.
老天 我又來了
Oh, my God. I did it again.
我太習慣叫它們孩子了
I'm so used to calling them our kids,
有的時候我忘記說清楚
sometimes I forget to clarify.
沒事 沒關系
No. It's fine.
德文可真是個小可愛啊
And isn't Devon just a little cutie?
那是丹妮詩 她是有意思的那一個
That's Denise. She's the funny one.
爸爸 我好無聊哦
Daddy, I'm bored.
好了 這樣不禮貌 莉莉
Okay, that's not polite, Lily.
稍安勿躁 小淑女
Now, hang on, little lady.
我來給你找點樂子
I'm about to get your party started.
這是一套斯里蘭卡買的手刻雙陸棋
This is a hand-carved backgammon set from Sri Lanka.
用手套 好好玩吧
Use the gloves. Have fun.
孩子們玩的時候
And while the kids are playing...
或者噎著的時候
Or choking.
不如你們和我們一起來廚房
...why don't you guys join us in the kitchen?
我來拿點酒
I'll grab us some wine.
我希望你不介意白葡萄酒
I hope you don't mind white.
我們因為一次紅酒事件損失了一個沙發
We lost a couch to a Cabernet incident,
特蘭特現在還有陰影
and Trent still gets flashbacks.
好了 去玩吧 孩子們
Okay. Go have fun, kids.
-好 -好好
- Yes! - Okay, okay.
第一點 不能喝果汁
First of all, no drinking juice.
讓我來從上到下檢查一遍
Let me pat him down.
好了 讓我來檢查一下你
All right. Let me check you.
好了 他沒問題
All right, he is clean.
等等 這是什么
Wait. What is this?
那東西怎么會在這
How did that get in there?
好了 好了 聽著 你過來
Okay, okay, look. Hey, come here.
坐在這 不要動
Just sit here. Do not move.
你可以和德文... 妮詩玩
You can play with Devon...ise.
你可以看你的卡車視頻
Uh, you can watch your truck videos.
你 別讓他離開你的視線
Hey, don't take your eyes off of him.
所以 確認一下 我不能有快樂童年嗎
So, just to be clear, I don't get any childhood?
拜托 上周我們還教你怎么做果餡餅呢
Oh, please. Last week, we taught you how to make flan.
是迪蘭
That's Dylan.
你需要我留下嗎
You need me to stick around?
不用 我剛剛在樓下練習該說什么
Nope. I was just downstairs practicing what to say,
我準備好面對每種可能的情景了
and I am prepared for every possible scenario.
來吧
Okay.
-你好 親愛的 -不
- Hello, love! - Oh, no.
我也想你 海莉
I missed you, too, Haley.
大驚喜
Surprise!
阿爾文從瑞士打電話給我
Arvin called me from Switzerland
因為他想給你個驚喜
'cause he wanted to surprise you,
所以我偷偷去機場把他接來了
so I snuck to the airport and picked him up.
真不敢相信我們沒被發現
I can't believe we got away with it!
-乖乖 又擊掌 -沒錯
- Oh, good. This again. - Yeah!
-快進來 -快看我
- Uh, come inside! - Look at me!
我去泡點茶
I'm gonna go make some tea!
是啊 快看他
Yeah, look at him!
不要接近那扇門
Get away from that door
鄧菲先生
Oh, hey, Mr. Dunphy.
你傷了我的"心"
You broke my heart.
迪蘭
Look, Dylan --
無需解釋 鄧非先生
No explanation necessary, Mr. D.
假如你不得不對我動粗并將我挾持
If you had to rough me up and take me hostage,
我相信你有充分的理由
I'm sure you had your reasons.
好吧 迪蘭 我們得先談談你這扮相
Okay, Dylan, first, we have to talk about your costume.
-你喜歡嗎 -非常棒
- Do you love it? - It's fantastic!
但時機不能更糟了
But the timing couldn't be worse.
-為什么 -你先坐
- Why? - Have a seat.
還是站著吧
You know what? Standing's fine.
聽著 阿爾文來了
Listen. Arvin's here.
他從瑞士飛回來給海莉驚喜
He flew back from Switzerland to surprise Haley.
我的對手也搞大示愛
I'm up against another grand gesture.
他扮成什么了
What's he dressed as?
他沒變裝 穿自己衣服來的
Nothing. Just-just himself.
我覺得我勝算很大
I like my chances.
我很抱歉沒回你電話
I'm sorry I didn't call you back.
我只是需要時間來思考迪蘭這件事
I just needed time to process the whole Dylan thing.
完全可以理解
That's totally understandable.
媽 接下來交給我吧
Mom, got it from here.
當然
Of course.
我們真的嚇到她了對嗎
We really got her, huh?
原諒我 我實在不想擊掌了
Forgive me. I can't anymore.
-我做不到 -好的
- I just -- I can't. - Okay.
海莉 我有話要告訴你
Haley, I need to tell you something.
我越過男女界限了
I transgressed.
你從女人變成了男人嗎
You were a woman?
不 不是
No. No.
在你告訴我那個吻的事后
After you told me about your kiss, um,
我徑直去了其他科學家常光顧的酒吧
I headed straight to a pub frequented by other scientists
長話短說
and, long story short,
我吻了一個核物理學家
I kissed a nuclear physicist.
我知道這話有些政治不正確
I know it's not PC to say,
但他們還真是所有科學學科里最"隨便"的了
but they really are the loosest of the scientific disciplines.
我原諒你
I forgive you.
就這樣 這么快
Just like that, so fast?
為什么不 我們同意彼此一樣有錯
Yeah. Why not? Let's just agree we're both equally guilty,
向前看 永不再討論這件事吧
move on, and never talk about it again.
聲明一下 我忍住了沒和她更進一步
For the record, it could have gone further.
我希望你能為此夸我一下
I-I just want a little credit for that.
好的
Okay.
媽
Mom!
怎么了
What?
我每天三點都這樣做
I do this every day at 3:00.
兄臺 你在做什么呢
Harpo, what are you doing?
研究你 創造角色
Studying you, creating a character.
你就假想我不在
Imagine I'm not here.
我沒那么有想象力
I'm not that creative.
不如你幫我一把實際離開
Maybe you could help me.
真粗魯 我喜歡
So gruff. Love it.
-我走 -我走
- I'm leaving. - I'm leaving.
很好 你走
Good. You go.
瞧瞧你們
Look at you,
我的兩個好朋友
mis dos amigos!
瞧瞧 瞧瞧你們 我的兩個好朋友
Look at-look at you, mis dos amigos!
的確聽起來很像我
That does sound like me.
你真有天賦
You're so talented.
太奇怪了
Okay, that was strange.
歌洛莉亞最討厭別人模仿她
Gloria hates when people imitate her.
然后歌洛莉亞說"我的'爺'[鞋]哪去了
And then Gloria says, "Where are my 'chews'?
沒有'爺'我怎么去俱樂部
I cannot go to the club without my 'chews.'
你的傻狗把我的'爺'咬壞了"
Your stupid doggie chews my 'chews'!"
很好笑
Ay, funny.
曼尼 寶貝 來幫我揉揉腳踝
Manny, come rub my ankles, papi!
很好
Good, good.
不過你那個搞笑老頭的角色練得怎么樣了
But how is your funny old man character coming?
誰給我倒杯威士忌
Somebody get me a scotch
要和我的背痛一樣烈的
that's as stiff as my back.
再學一次
Do that again!
就靠這個發達了
That's the money!
你怎么知道她在練這個
How did you know she was doing that?
她特別支持我 這是她的主意
She is so supportive. It was her idea.
原來如此
And there it was.
歌洛莉亞和我一樣不喜歡那個怪胎住在家里
Gloria didn't want that weirdo here any more than I did.
她只是希望我來做壞人
She just wanted me to be the bad guy.
不過她可想得美
But the joke's on her,
因為我可以很短暫地對他人很友好
because, for short bursts of time, I can be quite nice.
我們在嘗試新的調味飯菜譜
We're trying out a new recipe for risotto.
我們去托斯卡納找松露
We went truffle hunting in Tuscany,
偷偷多夾帶回來一些
and we brought back a few more than we declared.
你一個堂堂法院官員竟這么壞
Oh, and you, an officer of the court. So naughty.
別擔心 我們沒那么死板
Don't worry. We're cool.
我們的生發劑也是墨西哥弄回來的
We get our Propecia in Mexico.
多跟我們說說托斯卡納的事
Tell us more about Tuscany.
記得我們攢錢計劃去旅行嗎
Remember when we were saving up to go there?
后來那筆錢用在什么上面了
What did we end up blowing that money on?
-莉莉 -是啊
- Lily. - Right.
你們的生活聽起來真多彩多姿
Oh, well, your life sounds so exciting.
你們的房子這么漂亮 全是好東西
Your house is so beautiful, with such nice things.
他們不需要把錢花在牙齒矯正
Well, they don't have to spend their money on orthodontia,
-芭蕾課和大學基金上 -是啊
- ballet lessons, and college funds. - Yeah.
這山望著那山高
The grass is greener.
你們的山的確更高
Your grass is greener.
我們都沒辦法讓卡爾在家里尿尿
We can't seem to get Cal to pee indoors.
你的家庭看起來很美好
Well, your family seems great.
米奇爾在單位也鋒芒畢露
And, Mitchell, you are killing it at the office.
真的嗎
Really?
因為我覺得我接到的
Because I-I feel like I'm kind of getting
都是不起眼 入門級的官司
more low-profile, starter cases.
我要是你就不會擔心
Uh, I wouldn't worry about that.
其實我最近接了一起大官司
There's actually a big case that I am working on,
我認為你...
I think you will --
我的天
Oh, my God.
-什么聲音 -快去
- What was that?! - Go! Go!
拜托千萬是他家孩子惹的禍
Please let it be one of their kids.
你們在這呢
There you are!
海莉 你有空嗎
Hey. Uh, Haley, do you have a sec?
你不介意的話 我倆有點脫不開身
If you don't mind, we were kind of in the middle of something.
菲爾 你為什么要打擾他們倆
Phil, what are you doing intruding on these two?
我辦公室里有樣東西得給海莉看看
I just need to show Haley something in my office.
我剛才在打掃 偶然看到一個舊娃娃
I was doing a little cleaning, and I came across this old doll
過去她特別喜歡
that used to mean a lot to her.
你不能直接處理掉它嗎
Can't you just get rid of the doll?
本來要處理 但我真的認為
I started to, but it really seems like
你該自己去 有個了結
something you should do, you know, for closure.
你說得對
You're right.
等等 娃娃還需要了結嗎
Wait. You need closure from a doll?
感覺有點怪
That seems odd.
畢竟我16歲起就和那個娃娃一起睡了
Well, I did sleep with that thing since I was like 16.
不
Oh, no.
迪蘭
Dylan.
迪蘭怎么會在這
What is Dylan doing here?
他來搞大示愛
He's making a grand gesture.
不和海莉談談他不肯走
He won't leave until he talks to Haley.
我的天 不過是一個吻而已
Oh, my God. It was one kiss.
又傻又天真的克萊爾
Poor, naive Claire.
是兩個吻
It was two kisses.
你是怎么摻和進來的
You have something to do with this?
海莉一直對他玩人間蒸發
Haley was ghosting him.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
你也太不潮了
You are so not hip.
她不肯回他電話
She wouldn't call him back,
所以我叫她做正確的事
so I told her to do the right thing
當面有個了結 或者隨便怎樣
and end it -- or whatever -- in person.
"隨便怎樣" 那可不行
"Or whatever"? No "Or whatever."
她從青春期起就"隨便怎樣"了
She's been "Or whatever-ing" since puberty.
她是時候成熟起來了
It is time for her to grow up.
無所謂
Doesn't matter. Look,
歸根結底我們對她的期望是一樣的
we both want the same thing for her in the end.
-絕對的 -沒錯
- Absolutely. - Right.
讓她自己做出選擇
For her to make her own decision.
當然 唯一的選擇是 阿爾文
Of course. The only decision is...Arvin.
我同意 阿爾文很出眾
I agree. Arvin is very impressive.
但你該知道迪蘭最近
But you should know Dylan has been
在勤勉地讀護理學院
putting himself through nursing school,
在醫院工作 跑步
working at the hospital, running.
別告訴我你是真心在維護那家伙
You're not honestly making a case for that guy?
那家伙會為海莉出生入死
That guy would take a bullet for Haley.
你為什么對他感情這么深
Why are you so invested in him?
因為我當年和他一樣
Because I was that guy!
我不管喜歡哪個女孩都配不上人家
I was the underdog with every girl I ever liked.
真窩心
That's very sweet.
可重點不在于你
But this isn't about you.
重點在于海莉
This is about Haley
是選擇受人尊敬 有魅力的科學家
being with a respected, charming scientist
還是選擇在莉莉哄騙下吃掉一盒蠟筆的家伙
versus a guy who Lily convinced to eat a box of crayons.
他只咬了一支蠟筆一口
It was one bite out of one crayon.
還是因為他被蒙著眼睛
It was only because he was blindfolded
手指又被手指鎖鎖住了
and trapped in a Chinese finger puzzle.
我不知道阿爾文會來
I had no idea Arvin was going to be here,
但我們改天再談好嗎
but can we please do this another time?
改天我就沒有這身裝扮了 海莉
I won't have the costume another time, Haley.
這就是陪你睡了多年的娃娃[美男]
So, this is the doll you slept with.
你也長得挺好看的
Hey, you're pretty handsome yourself.
我有太多問題了
So many questions.
第一 你要是因為吻他而難過
First -- why have you snuck 'round to see the bloke
又為什么偷偷摸摸見他
you supposedly feel terrible about kissing?
我不是炫耀 但大多數情況下
Yo, I hope this doesn't sound braggy, but for the most part,
人們吻過我后一點都不難過
people do not feel terrible about kissing me.
你們倆打住
Okay, guys, stop.
聽好了 這位好傻好天真的朋友
Listen to me, my simple friend.
我剛坐了14小時飛機中間排的位子
I just spent 14 hours in a middle seat.
我勸你最好別擋老子的道
I suggest you get out of my space.
我還要建議你下次去做有逃生門那排呢
Well, I suggest, next time, you ask about an exit row.
雖然還是可能得做到中間排 但好歹夠伸腿
It could still be a middle seat, but you'd have more leg room.
你給我走
You have to go!
夠了 停止打架或者隨便怎樣
Enough! Stop fighting or whatever this is.
阿爾文 你在這里啊
Arvin! There you are!
你也好啊 迪蘭
Oh. Hi, Dylan.
如往常一般容光煥發啊 鄧菲太太
Radiant as ever, Mrs. D.
海莉 趕緊讓他滾啊
Haley, tell him to leave.
我來試試緩解這場面吧
Let me see if I can defuse the situation.
媽 老爸 別再插手我的人生
Mom, Dad, stop meddling in my life.
現在都出去
Outside now!
-行吧 -立刻
- All right. - Now!
好好好
Okay. Okay.
快幫忙 我不知道該怎么辦了
Help me. I don't know what to do.
我的面具
My mask!
我們真的超級對不起
We are so, so sorry.
我試過要擋住他了
I tried to block him.
他假動作騙我去救玻璃青蛙了
He faked going for the glass frog.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
深呼吸 寶貝 深呼吸
Breathe, honey. Breathe.
我們能修好嗎
Can we fix it?
不一定啊 你有沒有非洲第一高峰上
Oh, I don't know. Do you happen to have any clay
因融雪而成的黏土呢
from the melted runoff of Kilimanjaro?
因為它就是用這材料做的
Because that's what it's made of!
這是我們第一次去坦桑尼亞時得到的
We got it on our first trip to Tanzania.
被治好他牛皮癬的薩滿所加持過
It was blessed by the shaman that healed his psoriasis.
我們很樂意去找替代品補償你的損失
Of course we'll be happy to pay to replace it.
這東西無可替代
It's irreplaceable!
天啊
Oh, my God.
又開始發作了
It's back. Oh.
我們真覺得道再多歉也不夠
We cannot apologize enough.
這話可能還真說對了
That's probably true.
我去弄午飯
I'll go get lunch.
慘了 這真的很糟糕
Okay, this is a disaster.
但你可還有留意到他有提起
I know, but is any part of you still hearing
"第一次去坦桑尼亞時"
"first trip to Tanzania"?
他就差一點就要把那個案子給我了
He was just about to offer me the case I want.
沒事 以后還會有別的案子
Well, there'll be other cases.
一個高級伴游 還有非法武器銷售
an escort, and illegal arms sales, okay?
我想要將他們繩之以法
I want to bring them to justice.
而且他們已經賣出了電影翻拍版權
Plus, they've already sold the movie rights.
有可能會是帥哥男星瑞恩·高斯林演我呢
I could be played by Ryan Gosling.
是是是 親愛的 要胸懷大志
That's it, honey. Aim high.
天啊 這下怎么辦
Oh, my God. What can we do?
我們該怎么解釋
What can we do?
-快點 快咬我腳踝 -你說什么
- Quick. Bite my ankle. - Excuse me?
快點 趁他們回來之前咬 這樣我就能說
Hurry, before they come back. I'm gonna tell them
是狗咬了我 這樣面具的事就能抵消了
the dog did it. It'll cancel out the mask.
快咬
Just do it.
大力點 得留下傷痕
Harder. It needs to scar me.
這絕對給我心靈留下了傷痕
It's definitely scarring me.
得讓他們相信是狗咬的
They need to believe a dog did it.
這個嘛... 如果你們...
Oh. Well, if you're --
如果你們午飯要讓我們等這么久
you're gonna make us wait so long to eat,
看到這一幕也不算什么奇怪的事吧
this shouldn't come as a surprise.
歌洛莉亞 快來看
Gloria, come here!
你一定得來看 她太出色了
You got to see this. She's on fire.
你快瞧瞧
Now, check this out.
我能給她出任何題
I can throw anything at her,
她都能瞬間演得超爆笑
and she can make comedy gold out of it.
來
Here. Um...
約翰·特拉沃爾塔在潛水艇里
John Travolta in a submarine.
懂了吧 因為潛艇里很狹窄
Yeah, because a submarine is small.
歌洛莉亞你說得真對 她超搞笑
You were right, Gloria. She's hilarious.
再來一題吧
Do another one. Um...
霸王龍打排球
T. Rex in a volleyball game.
你看看
Look at that.
霸王龍的小短手很難殺球
It's hard to spike with little arms.
杰 能借一步說話嗎
Jay, can I talk to you in there for a second?
行行行 沒問題
Yeah, yeah. All right.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
太好笑了
What a hoot!
你耍什么陰招呢 老鬼
What is your game, old man?
沒招啊 我超喜歡
Nothing. I'm loving this.
我現在只怕她哪天火了會想搬走
My only fear is that she might hit it big and leave us.
你當我傻啊
You think I'm an idiot?
沒人會覺得剛才的表演好笑
Nobody thinks that that is funny.
你說實話 你明明比我更想要她滾蛋
Be honest -- you want her out of here more than I do.
行 但我不想當那種
Okay, fine, but I don't want to be the mother
討厭自己兒子女朋友的媽媽
that hates her son's girlfriends.
我也不想再當家里那個壞人了
I don't want to be the villain anymore.
但這是你的職責啊
But that's your job.
我是負責安靜有趣的母親
I am the quiet and fun one.
你是沒看到她模仿你的樣子嗎
Have you not heard her impression of you?
像到爆炸
It's dead-on.
你想把她趕走你就自己動手
You want to get rid of her, you do it.
不需要 因為我假裝喜歡她的持續力
I won't have to, because I can pretend
將會比你長很多
that I like Sherry longer than you can.
你會先受不了的
You will crack first.
You will crack first!
雪莉 你不能住這里了
Sherry, you cannot stay here.
什么 為什么啊
What? Why?
因為你快把我逼瘋了
Because you're driving me crazy.
我還以為你挺喜歡我呢
But I thought you liked me.
孩子 我也不知道說什么 她很難相處
What can I say, kid? She's rough.
我去幫你拿行李
Let me get your bag.
我回來啦 你們猜怎么著
Hey, I'm back! Guess what.
我以前幫主任寫的那些書法有回報了
All that calligraphy I've done for the dean paid off.
他說我可以跟你住一起了
He said you can stay with me.
你媽媽剛說她討厭我
Your mom just told me she hates me.
媽 你為什么會說這種話
Mom, why would you say that?
落幕
And scene!
為什么我不能叫迪蘭走
Why can't I tell Dylan to leave?
因為你對你人生首次真心成熟
Because you are scared of the first real, adult relationship
對象還完美的戀情感到惶恐 所以想躲回舊愛
with the perfect man, and you're clinging to the past.
也可能你跟迪蘭有著十分特別的緣分
Or you and Dylan have a special connection
而且你還愛著他
and you still love him.
完全沒幫到我
Not helping.
天啊 他們倆都是很好的男人
God, they're both such great guys,
但型真的好不一樣
but they're so different.
我到底該怎么選啊
How am I supposed to choose?
你們當時怎么選中彼此的
How did you guys do it?
乖女兒 我...
Well, sweetheart, I --
這題我真是幫不上你了
I'm not gonna be any help here.
從我見到你媽媽的那一秒 我就拋棄了選擇
From the minute I met your mom, there was no choice.
她聰明又堅強
She was smart. She was strong.
她對父親的怨恨恰好夠愛上我這樣的人
She resented her father just enough to go for a guy like me.
她... 她讓我的人生得到了平衡
She -- She gave my life balance,
我現在早已無法想象失去她會如何
and now I can't imagine it without her.
而且她...
Also, she's --
真的長得超正
she's crazy hot.
老媽
Mom?
首先呢
Well, first of all, um,
我對能說出剛才那種話的男人沒抵抗力
I'm a sucker for guys who say things like that.
你爸爸是我見過人最好 最積極正面的人
Your dad is the nicest, most positive person I know,
他總能幫我找到生命中的那些歡樂
and he always helps me find the fun in life.
而且他... 現在看起來還是超順眼的呢
And, uh, he is still real easy on the peepers.
我們真的很幸運呢
Aww. We really are lucky.
對啊
Oh, I know.
我都忘了我們剛才在吵什么了
I forgot what we were even fighting about.
我也是
Me too.
你們沒在吵架 剛才是在討論我的煩惱
You weren't fighting. We were talking about my problem.
-對哦 -親愛的
- Oh, yeah. - Oh, honey,
你最好還是忘了我們說的那些話
you should probably just ignore everything we said
然后想象分別與他們在一起的人生會如何
and try to imagine your life with each of them.
你能看到什么畫面
What do you see?
跟阿爾文在一起 能預見到又大又漂亮的房子
I guess, with Arvin, I see a big, beautiful house...
阿爾文
Arvin!
阿爾文你等等我
Arvin, wait!
房子里擺滿了各種書籍
...lined with books,
有趣的人們來家里拜訪
interesting people coming in and out,
與一個出色的男人一起養大孩子
raising kids with a brilliant man.
我真的很對不起 我...
I'm so sorry. I...
沒事啦
Oh, well.
現在我可能得用我的聰明才智干壞事了
Now I may have to use my genius for evil.
而你就是我的惡人黑化起源
You're my origin story.
什么
What?
每個超級壞蛋都有個令他們那么...
Every supervillain has a reason they're so...
算了 或許這樣最好
You know, maybe this is for the best.
與迪蘭在一起呢 我能預見
With Dylan, I see us in a cute, little place
我們小而溫馨 但需要努力改善的家
that needs a ton of work.
我們或許沒辦法擁有各種最好的東西
We may not have all the nicest things,
但永遠會有音樂與歡聲笑語
but there's music and laughing,
而且我知道我能永遠當自己
and I know I can always be myself,
他也會永遠愛真正的我
and he'll always love me for it.
我剛剛結束一段戀情
I just got out of a relationship.
我現在真的是一團亂
I'm, like, a complete mess.
那太好了 我就喜歡一團亂
That's perfect. I love messes.
我們能不能... 退后一步
Can we, uh, take a step back
就單純從約個會開始
and just go out on a date?
沒問題
Sure.
座駕已在此等候多時
Your chariot awaits.
我這樣坐不進我的車嘛
I couldn't fit in my car, you know.
好 我就先...
Okay, I'll just -- Oh!
我們倆看來是永遠也別想退休了吧
We're never gonna be able to retire, are we?
別想了
Nope.
很遺憾那個很有料的案子沒到手
Ah. I'm sorry the juicy trial didn't work out.
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
如果我能有機會重來
Yeah. I-I guess if I had to do it all over again,
我不會再叫你咬我
I wouldn't have told you to bite me.
好奇怪啊 我居然什么都沒問就去咬了
Weird how I just went along with that, no questions.
說到有機會重來
And speaking of doing it all over again,
你有后悔過要孩子嗎
do you ever regret having kids?
當然不啦
Of course not.
這么說吧 我有過回想過去
I mean, do I sometimes look back
然后希望一切與現在不同嗎
and wish everything was different?
如果你的答案是"有" 那就是有后悔
If you say "yes," that is regret.
那沒有 因為如果沒有孩子們
Then, no, because if we didn't have them
我會變成像特倫特 一個緊張兮兮的神經病
I would be Trent, an uptight lunatic
會因為一個小飾物壞了就崩潰
who falls apart over a broken tchotchke.
孩子們能開拓你的視野
I mean, kids give you perspective.
讓你理解什么才是真正重要的東西
You realize what's important,
讓你能放開那些...
to let go of...
我們家最后的好東西也碎了
And there goes our last nice thing.
感謝老天給了我們一個解脫
Thank God we're free now.